Skills

Tech Skills - JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, React JS, Git, Unit Testing (Jest & Enzyme), Firebase BaaS, APIs, Authentication, GitHub, Hosting, Pair Programming, Agile, Scrum, MongoDB, SAS, SQL, Python (basic), Selenium & Postgresql.

Communication - I have often had to present as part of my professional experience, sometimes I found this challenging due to being relatively new to it. As a result I have worked off my own back as well as on the _nology boot camp to improve my presentation skills.

Teamwork - I always enjoy being a valued member of a team, my experience making friends for life at Co-op bank allowed the team I was in to be excellent under pressure.

Skill Learning and Self Improvement - Evidenced by my _nology Bootcamp, as well as learning other programming languages in my spare time.

Problem Solving - From my hobbies to professional project experience, problem solving is central to what i do.

Positive Outlook: Being genetically positive has cursed me with an inherent like for everyone i meet. This allows me to empathise with people from all walks of life.

Hobbies

Brazilliant Jiu Jitsu - Purple belt

Undoubtedly one of the best things i have done and has given me a sense of community and catharsis.

Travelling

I have so far been to: Singapore, Sri Lanka, Australia, New Zealand, Hong Kong, Cuba, Copenhagen, France, Greece, Italy, California, Portugal & Andora

Climbing

Climbing was a central part of my life in Manchester having met lifelong friends at the bouldering wall.

Surfing

This is something I find fun even though I'm not very good at it.

Side Projects

DIY Sauna "Lockdown" Project designed and built a sauna in my back garden.

Stocks and Shares Project using Python , Selenium, Postgresql and Talend ETL Studio to build a Postgresql database with calculations and logic to signal undervalued shares.

Plant Watering Project watering plants using a Raspberry Pi.

Education

University of Leicester 2007-2010
BSc (Hons) Economics 2:1

3 year course covering economics and statistics.

A 10 year career in financial database development has given me an aptitude for solving problems code and commercial project experience. My interest in Tech has allowed my creativity to flow in a way like never before.

I have used my professional experience to create a plant watering system and a Stocks and Shares Database. I have developed hobbies which have grown over time and added to my problem solving abilities.

The highlight of my _nology Bootcamp was being project manager for a week on our project. This involved presenting the product to the client, learning about how to make effective tickets and the trials of merging shared work to GitHub.

Having learned so much in such a short time period. I am tremendously excited to imagine what I can achieve in Tech in the coming years.

Professional Training

_nology 2020

An intense training course, covering front end development in several Languages. It also focussed on weekly challenges to cement technical knowledge, presenting, a client project and a multitude of websites, React apps and a full stack (node.js) Climbing Location app. Please check out my portfolio for more of my work. Highlight - Client Project:

- Client Project (No1SouthEast) This was the creation of a React discount app for local restaurants and bars.
- I was able to be project manager for a week which involved, sorting the tickets for the next sprint, and learning how to make them small and achievable
- I was also project manager for our first big GIT merge before presenting the product to the client.
 This was a long night to say the least.

Infront - Public Speaking Course-

2019

This was a weekend course covering presenting overcoming fear and being comfortable in front of a group.

Previous Employment

Build Lead /Analyst - Co-operative Bank 2018 - 2020

Working on a Project, Involved the redevelopment, build and testing of the existing capital modelling process. After this project I was working on migration and reconciliation to a new SAS environment.

Contract SAS Developer - Lloyds 2015 - 2016

Involved working as part of a project team to re-develop, document and implement existing analyst code into a big data environment.

Senior SAS Consultant - Base3 Ltd 2011 - 2015

This involved training and then 2 placements, My senior responsibility involved mentoring new starters and making sure they were comfortable with the pace of the project.